<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet href="xhtml-default.css" type="text/css" media="screen, aural, print" ?>
<!DOCTYPE html PUBLIC "-//W3C//DTD XHTML Basic 1.1//EN"
    "http://www.w3.org/TR/xhtml-basic/xhtml-basic11.dtd">
<html xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml" xml:lang="en" lang="en" manifest="SpeakGoodChinese3.appcache" >
<head>
<link rel="shortcut icon" href="sgc.png" />
<link rel="manifest" href="manifest.json" />
<link rel="icon" sizes="192x192" href="sgc.png" />
<meta name="viewport" content="width=device-width" />
<meta name="mobile-web-app-capable" content="yes" />
<meta http-equiv="Content-Language" content="en" />
<title lang="en" xml:lang="en" dir="ltr">Credits - SpeakGoodChinese</title>
</head>
<body>
<h1 style='text-align: center'>
		SpeakGoodChinese 3 <br />
		Shuō hǎo Zhōngwén <br />
		说好中文
</h1>
<h2 style='text-align: center; font-style: italic; '>
Dedicated to the memory of Guanqin Chen
</h2>
 
<p style='text-align: center'>For more information, visit our website: <a href="http://www.speakgoodchinese.org">http://www.speakgoodchinese.org</a></p>
 
<p>
SpeakGoodChinese was supported by grant 6046 from the Digitale Universiteit<br />
The SpeakGoodChinese Team:
<ul>
<li><strong>Guanqin Chen</strong> (HRO) - Founder and project manager, Language and Teaching</li>
<li><strong>Zongyan Chen</strong> (HvA) - Language and Teaching</li>
<li><strong>Eveline van Hagen</strong> (Fontys) - Language and Teaching</li>
<li><strong>Stefan de Konink</strong> (UvA) - Lead programmer, User Interface</li>
<li><strong>Lifeng Liu</strong> (HRO) - Language assistant</li>
<li><strong>Rob van Son</strong> (UvA) - Coordinator technical work, Webapp, Speech technology, GUI</li>
<li><strong>Dennis Vierkant</strong> (UT) - User Interface and Language</li>
<li><strong>David Weenink</strong> (UvA) - Praat programming, Algorithms</li>
</ul>
</p>

<p>
SpeakGoodChinese 3 would not have been possible without the extensive help of Paul Boersma. We would like
to thank Zhao Ran (赵冉) and Yitna Firdyiwek of the University of Virginia and Takahiro Higashi (東孝拓) of 
Peking University for their help in integrating SGC in the classroom and their many suggestions and tests.
We also want to thank Tristian van Berkom, J.E. Raaijmakers, R. van Rijsselt and S. Verhagen.
</p>   
<p>
Translations: Japanese - Takahiro Higashi (東孝拓); Chinese - Takahiro Higashi (東孝拓) and Wang Huiting(王慧婷) 
</p>   
<p>
Copyrights © 2007-2016 by Hogeschool Rotterdam, Rob van Son (ACLC/UvA/NKI) - R.J.J.H.vanSon@gmail.com
</p>   
<pre>
This program is free software: you can redistribute it and/or modify
it under the terms of the GNU General Public License as published by
the Free Software Foundation, either version 2 of the License, or
(at your option) any later version.

This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful,
but WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.  See the
GNU General Public License for more details.
 
You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
along with this program.  If not, see <a href="http://www.gnu.org/licenses/">http://www.gnu.org/licenses</a>.
</pre>   
<div id="VERSION" style="font-style: italic; font-size: 1vm; " >V: fc812bf513 </div> 
</body>
</html>
